<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Make History Today on HackUrCulture</title>
    <link>http://example.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Make History Today on HackUrCulture</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>City of JohannesburgPublic library</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/cityofjohannesburgpubliclibrary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/cityofjohannesburgpubliclibrary/</guid>
      <description>Johannesburg&amp;rsquo;s public libraries are hubs of education, giving residents access to books, magazines and audio-visual materials. Besides lending out material, the City’s libraries offer a wide-range of other services including literacy classes, storytelling sessions for youngsters, classroom support, gatherings for older residents and literary competitions. They are also the venues for lectures, exhibitions, and talks. Libraries can be found across the City’s seven regions, and mobile satellite centres also travel to far-flung areas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>District 6 Museum</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/disctrict6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/disctrict6/</guid>
      <description>About The ‘Hands Off District Six’ conference of 1988 led to the formation of the District Six Museum Foundation in 1989. The Foundation worked towards the establishment of the Museum which was launched on 10 December 1994 with its inaugural exhibition called Streets: Retracing District Six.
 See GLAM&amp;rsquo;s intro here  Challenges: Remote access to archive and collection, changing business models, sustainability, education of staff to actively take steps to digitization, policy for the digital transformation of archive and collection, access to talent, implementing digital transformation, developing the correct naming convention for digital artifacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Goethe-Institut Cameroon African German Phrasebook</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/africangermanphrasebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/africangermanphrasebook/</guid>
      <description>The idea for this special phrase book was developed during the workshop series &amp;ldquo;Going Kompyuta&amp;rdquo; at the Goethe-Institut Cameroon. The aim was to bring together modern information technology and the promotion of African languages.
The Android app currently offers 150 daily terms in 51 different languages. Up to three languages can be displayed simultaneously next to each other. The terms are clearly arranged in 13 categories. Simply clicking on a term starts the audio output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HEVA</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/heva/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/heva/</guid>
      <description>Africa’s first dedicated finance, business support and knowledge facility for creative industries.
http://www.hevafund.com/
Challenges: Implementing digital transformation
Data set available:  anecdotal evidence shared by representatives  Problem statement  Not facing the institution directly, but are facing our beneficiaries. Finding a way to increase the interactivity of 3D renders of African cultural objects. Innovative digital merchandising to augment attendance/memories and give souvenirs of a cultural experience (eg. a play, a musical performance, album launch etc)  Tags </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Sciences Research Council</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/humansciencesresearchcouncil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/humansciencesresearchcouncil/</guid>
      <description>Iziko Museums of South Africa operates 11 national museums in Cape Town. It is one of the premier cultural institutions in South Africa. The museums house natural history, social history and art collections in magnificent, historic buildings which in themselves are national treasures.
https://www.iziko.org.za/about
Challenges: Remote access to archive, Education of staff to actively take steps towards digitisation, Policy, standards and workflow for digital transformation, Access to talent, High costs of digitisation, Implementing digital transformation, Developing the right naming convention for cultural heritage artefacts with unknown or scarce historical information, taking into account community knowledge and narratives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Library of South Africa - NLSA</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/nlsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/nlsa/</guid>
      <description>https://www.nlsa.ac.za/
Challenges: Awareness, sustainability, Remote access to cultural heritage data, artefacts, archives, policy for digital transformation, access to talent, Implementing digital transformation, Edutainment
Data set available:  Ityala la Mawele publication (Part of the Reprint of the South African classics Project) Chaka publication (Part of our Reprint of the Classics Project) Special collections Supporting metadata  Link
Problem statement  Making the documentary heritage accessible on-line thereby increasing the NLSA&amp;rsquo;s reach in making the collections accessible to South Africans and the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Queer and Lesbian archive (GALA)</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/gala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/gala/</guid>
      <description>Gala is a centre for Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transgender, Intersex and Queer (LGBTIQ) culture and education in South Africa. Our mission is to act as a catalyst for the production, preservation and dissemination of knowledge on the history, culture and contemporary experiences of LGBTIQ people.
https://gala.co.za//
Challenges: Awareness of the institution and its archive, education of staff to actively take steps towards digitisation, problems of privacy and safety around digitization and open access, policy for the digital transformation of the archive, Implementing digital transformation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South African Classic Project</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/sadilar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/sadilar/</guid>
      <description>About The South African Centre for Digital Language Resources (SADiLaR) is a national centre supported by the Department of Science and Innovation (DSI) as part of the new South African Research Infrastructure Roadmap (SARIR).
“SARIR is a high-level strategic and systemic intervention to provide research infrastructure across the entire public research system, building on existing capabilities and strengths, and drawing on future needs.” (DST SARIR brochure).
SADiLaR has an enabling function, with a focus on all official languages of South Africa, supporting research and development in the domains of language technologies and language-related studies in the humanities and social sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South African Classic Project</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/wits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/wits/</guid>
      <description>Challenges: Awareness of the institution and its collection/archive, remote access to cultural heritage archive/collection
Data set available:  To be determined  Problem statement  Create an online platform that will house content which provides an additional layer of engagement with our exhibitions and education programme. Use the online platform to bridge language barriers; thus allowing us to reach a wider audience. Develop the online platform in such a way that it can be used as a way to connect and engage with the museum, without being there physically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>South African History Archive</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/saha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/saha/</guid>
      <description>About The South African History Archive (SAHA) is an independent human rights archive dedicated to documenting, supporting and promoting greater awareness of past and contemporary struggles for justice through archival practices and outreach, and the utilisation of access to information laws.
 See GLAM&amp;rsquo;s intro here  Challenges: Sustainability, digital access to archives, awareness of the institution and its collection/archive
Data set available:  Oral recordings and texts Photos and posters  link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Nest Collective</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/thenestcollective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/thenestcollective/</guid>
      <description>The Nest Collective is a multidisciplinary arts collective living and working in Nairobi. Founded in 2012, we create works in film, music, fashion, visual arts and literature&amp;hellip;
http://www.thisisthenest.com/
Challenges: Implementing digital transformation
Data set available: This data is anecdotal. When our events were very public, we had groups of people doing ticketing as well as actual bouncers who would do checks as briefed. Is there a digital way to do this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Dash</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/bookdash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/bookdash/</guid>
      <description>About Book Dash believes that every child should own one hundred books by the age of five. To that end, we gather creative professionals who volunteer to create new, African storybooks that anyone can freely translate, print and distribute. In this way, we have vastly reduced the costs involved in putting high-quality books in children’s hands and hearts.
 See GLAM&amp;rsquo;s intro here  Challenges: Awareness, Sustainability, Edutainment
Data set available: 20 different books from the Book Dash collection</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
